domcop.com 2018-09-03

# DomCop Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

Your privacy is critically important to us. At DomCop.com, we have adapted the privacy policy from [Wordpress](https://automattic.com/privacy/) that follow a few fundamental principles:

  * \- We are thoughtful about the personal information we ask you to provide and the personal information that we collect about you through the operation of our services.
  * \- We store personal information for only as long as we have a reason to keep it.
  * \- We aim for full transparency on how we gather, use, and share your personal information.

Below is our Privacy Policy, which incorporates and clarifies these principles.

#### Who We Are and What This Policy Covers

We are the folks behind DomCop a popular expired domains search tool.

This Privacy Policy applies to information that we collect about you when you use our SaaS based expired domains search tool

Throughout this Privacy Policy we'll refer to our website as "Services." And if you'd like to learn more about which DomCop.com company is the controller of information about you, take a look at the section below on Controllers and Responsible Companies.

Below we explain how we collect, use, and share information about you, along with the choices that you have with respect to that information.

#### Information We Collect

We only collect information about you if we have a reason to do so-for example, to provide our Services, to communicate with you, or to make our Services better.

##### _Information You Provide to Us_

It's probably no surprise that we collect information that you provide to us. The amount and type of information depends on the context and how we use the information. Here are some examples:

  * \- **Email Address:** We ask you to sign up for an account at DomCop using your Email Address. We do not require any other additional information.
  * \- **Communications With Us (Hi There!):** You may also provide us information when you respond to surveys, communicate with us about a support question, or post a question about your site in our public forums.

##### _Information We Collect Automatically_

We also collect some information automatically:

  * \- **Log Information:** Like most online service providers, we collect information that web browsers, mobile devices, and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, IP address, unique device identifiers, language preference, referring site, the date and time of access, operating system, and mobile network information. We collect log information when you browse our website DomCop.com. 
  * \- **Location Information:** We may determine the approximate location of your device from your IP address. We collect and use this information to, for example, calculate how many people visit our Services from certain geographic regions. We may also collect information about your precise location via our mobile apps (when, for example, you post a photograph with location information) if you allow us to do so through your mobile device operating system's permissions.
  * \- **Information from Cookies & Other Technologies:** A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Pixel tags (also called web beacons) are small blocks of code placed on websites and emails. DomCop.com uses cookies and other technologies like pixel tags to help us identify and track visitors, usage, and access preferences for our Services, as well as track and understand email campaign effectiveness and to deliver targeted ads.

### How And Why We Use Information

##### _Purposes for Using Information_

We use information about you as mentioned above and for the purposes listed below:

  * \- To provide our Services-for example, to sign up for an account at DomCop;
  * \- To further develop and improve our Services-for example by adding new features that we think our users will enjoy or will help them with online marketing;
  * \- To monitor and analyze trends and better understand how users interact with our Services, which helps us improve our Services and make them easier to use;
  * \- To measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising;
  * \- To monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, protect the security of our Services, detect and prevent illegal activities, fight spam, and protect the rights and property of DomCop.com and others, which may result in us declining the use of our Services;
  * \- To communicate with you, for example through an email, about offers and promotions offered by DomCop.com and others we think will be of interest to you, solicit your feedback, or keep you up to date on DomCop.com and our other products; and
  * \- To personalize your experience using our Services, target our marketing messages to groups of our users (for example, those who have been our user for a certain length of time), and serve relevant advertisements.

##### _Legal Bases for Collecting and Using Information_

A note here for those in the European Union about our legal grounds for processing information about you under EU data protection laws, which is that our use of your information is based on the grounds that:

(1) The use is necessary in order to fulfill our commitments to you under our Terms of Service or other agreements with you or is necessary to administer your account–for example, in order to enable the browser add-on using an API key; or

(2) The use is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation; or

(3) The use is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or those of another person; or

(4) We have a legitimate interest in using your information–for example, to provide and update our Services, to improve our Services so that we can offer you an even better user experience, to safeguard our Services, to communicate with you, to measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition, to monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, and to personalize your experience; or

(5) You have given us your consent–for example before we place certain cookies on your device and access and analyze them later on.

### Sharing Information

##### _How We Share Information_

We do not sell our users' private personal information.

We share information about you in the limited circumstances spelled out below and with appropriate safeguards on your privacy:

  * \- **Subsidiaries, Employees, and Independent Contractors:** We may disclose information about you to our subsidiaries, our employees, and individuals who are our independent contractors that need to know the information in order to help us provide our Services or to process the information on our behalf. We require our subsidiaries, employees, and independent contractors to follow this Privacy Policy for personal information that we share with them.
  * \- **Business Transfers:** In connection with any merger, sale of company assets, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company, or in the unlikely event that DomCop.com goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would likely be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. If any of these events were to happen, this Privacy Policy would continue to apply to your information and the party receiving your information may continue to use your information, but only consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  * \- **With Your Consent:** We may share and disclose information with your consent or at your direction.
  * \- **Aggregated or De-Identified Information:** We may share information that has been aggregated or reasonably de-identified, so that the information could not reasonably be used to identify you. For instance, we may publish aggregate statistics about the use of our Services and we may share a hashed version of your email address to facilitate customized ad campaigns on other platforms.
  * \- **Published Support Requests:** And if you send us a request (for example, via a support email or one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish that request in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users.

#### How Long We Keep Information

We generally discard information about you when we no longer need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it–which are described in the section above on How and Why We Use Information–and we are not legally required to continue to keep it.

For example, we keep the web server logs that record information about a visitor to one of DomCop.com's websites, such as the visitor's IP address, browser type, and operating system, for approximately 30 days. We retain the logs for this period of time in order to, among other things, analyze traffic to DomCop.com's websites and investigate issues if something goes wrong on one of our websites.

#### Security

While no online service is 100% secure, we work very hard to protect information about you against unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction, and take reasonable measures to do so, such as monitoring our Services for potential vulnerabilities and attacks.

#### Choices

You have several choices available when it comes to information about you:

  * \- **Opt-Out of Electronic Communications:** You may opt out of receiving promotional messages from us. Just follow the instructions in those messages. If you opt out of promotional messages, we may still send you other messages, like those about your account and legal notices.
  * \- **Set Your Browser to Reject Cookies:** At this time, DomCop.com does not respond to "do not track" signals across all of our Services. However, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies before using DomCop.com's websites, with the drawback that certain features of DomCop.com's websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.
  * \- **Close Your Account:** While we'd be very sad to see you go, if you no longer want to use our Services, you can close your account. Please [email us for getting your account closed](mailto:akash@domcop.com). Please keep in mind that we may continue to retain your information after closing your account, as described in How Long We Keep Information above–for example, when that information is reasonably needed to comply with (or demonstrate our compliance with) legal obligations such as law enforcement requests, or reasonably needed for our legitimate business interests.

#### Your Rights

If you are located in certain countries, including those that fall under the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (AKA the "GDPR"), data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions provided by the law, including the rights to:

  * \- Request access to your personal data;
  * \- Request correction or deletion of your personal data;
  * \- Object to our use and processing of your personal data;
  * \- Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data; and
  * \- Request portability of your personal data.

You can usually access, correct, or delete your personal data using your account settings and tools that we offer, but if you aren't able to do that, or you would like to contact us about one of the other rights, scroll down to How to Reach Us to, well, find out how to reach us.

EU individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

#### Controllers and Responsible Company

DomCop.com's Services are provided by the parent company called Axeman Tech Pvt Ltd.

Axeman Tech Pvt Ltd  
502 B Anisha Apartments   
Yari Road, Versova  
Mumbai 400061  
Maharashtra  
India

#### How to Reach Us

If you have a question about this Privacy Policy, or you would like to contact us about any of the rights mentioned in the Your Rights section above, please [contact us](mailto:akash@domcop.com).

### Other Things You Should Know

##### _Ads and Analytics Services Provided by Others_

Ads appearing on any of our Services may be delivered by advertising networks. Other parties may also provide analytics services via our Services. These ad networks and analytics providers may set tracking technologies (like cookies) to collect information about your use of our Services and across other websites and online services. These technologies allow these third parties to recognize your device to compile information about you or others who use your device. This information allows us and other companies to, among other things, analyze and track usage, determine the popularity of certain content, and deliver advertisements that may be more targeted to your interests. Please note this Privacy Policy only covers the collection of information by DomCop.com and does not cover the collection of information by any third party advertisers or analytics providers.

#### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, DomCop.com may change its Privacy Policy from time to time. DomCop.com encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the change log below, and, in some cases, we may provide additional notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage, or sending you a notification through email). Your further use of the Services after a change to our Privacy Policy will be subject to the updated policy.

That's it! Thanks for reading.

Last Updated: 25th May 2018

View Terms of Service.
